[BORAQCHIN]
The House of Tolui is in ruins.
[♪ drum beats]
[wind blowing]
[BORAQCHIN] Uh?
♪
Oh, it disappeared.
[laughs]
[MÖGE] Boraqchin!
So this is where you are!
[BORAQCHIN] Hmm?
They've got all manner
of gemstones over there.
-Let's go look!
-Gemstones?
Yes! I hear
it's a caravan of traders
that returned from the west.
Come on already!
Wait a moment.
I'm afraid that gemstones
wouldn't look very flattering
on someone like me.
[MÖGE] Mm?
-[MÖGE] So what?
-Uh?
It can be plenty of fun
just to look around.
-[Möge chuckles]
-[BORAQCHIN] Uh...
Hurry up! [chuckles]
♪
[Kirgistani exclaims]
[Boraqchin gasps]
[MÖGE] Look at these.
Don't you think
that we could make
some lovely earrings
out of them?
Yes, they're splendid.
You should try to find something
for yourself, too.
Oh, no, not for me.
[Möge exclaims]
[Boraqchin gasps]
[MAN] I wouldn't bother
with that stone if I were you.
That one somehow
found its way
into the batch of gemstones
we recently procured.
It's honestly a meddlesome stone
that crumbles
whenever it's exposed to light.
Crumbles? In the light?
As if by fate,
I discovered
this shabby-looking rock
amidst the dazzling gemstones,
and found myself
strangely fascinated by it.
A simple stone.
That was how it all began.
[♪ opening theme song playing]
[BORAQCHIN] Uh?
It's coated in a powder.
[sighs]
This hard stone is already
beginning to wear away
in a few days of sunlight.
How curious.
♪
After reading up on it,
I learned this stone
was called sandarac
and was known in the east
for its medicinal properties.
Taken in appropriate doses,
it could heal abscesses
and restore one's vigor.
However, when heated
over a fire,
it turns into a white substance
known as arsenic...
A deadly poison
that dissolves in water
and is devoid of taste or odor.
This brittle rock
unfit to be a gemstone.
It's just...
It's just so fascinating.
In the following year,
Genghis Khan met his demise.
As his consorts,
Möge and I were uncertain
of our fate,
but ended up being taken
as wives by our stepson Ögedei.
And I...
Somehow became
Ögedei's primary empress.
Why did he choose me?
I thought it was simply
because I was the eldest.
But...
Wow! A rock that crumbles
in the light?
[BORAQCHIN]
A trifling hobby of mine.
Please pay it no mind.
Very well. It does seem
beyond my understanding.
That said, I am happy to learn
about something you enjoy.
Please let me know
if there are any other rocks
you would want.
I'll make sure you get them.
Yes. But...
why do so much for me?
[ÖGEDEI] The desire
to obtain something...
That is the urge that sets
the world in motion.
[Boraqchin gasps softly]
♪
I have my own desire.
that this steppe will someday
be a vast market
that connects east and west.
Can you see it?
Eastern and western
cultures alike
passing through to do trade.
In such a world,
we won't need to venture off
to wage war and plunder.
People and goods
will gather here willingly.
[Boraqchin gasps softly]
Thanks for your offer.
I'm really looking
for more books.
I want to learn about the nature
of these stones.
Very well then.
I'm truly glad
you're my empress.
Thank you for accepting.
Tolui and the others
would never understand
what I hope to accomplish.
That's why
I want someone like you
who can truly
appreciate it by my side.
[Boraqchin gasps softly]
♪
[BORAQCHIN]
The House of Tolui's power
will inhibit him
from acting freely.
Can nothing be done about that?
Empress Boraqchin...
Your new physician is here
to see you.
-[Möge chuckles]
-And Lady Möge as well.
Hello!
[PHYSICIAN] Oh, my goodness.
[BORAQCHIN]
I'm quite fond of rocks
that change
appearance and behavior
under heat or light.
Eastern physicians
like yourself are well-versed
in such matters, am I correct?
Indeed.
[Möge breathes softly]
[PHYSICIAN] By any chance,
have you heard
of the Daoist doctrine
known as waidan?
I'm not familiar.
Using fire or water
to refine stones
like these ones,
they tried to concoct elixirs
of immortality.
But inaccurate methods resulted
in a deadly poison instead.
[BORAQCHIN]
It was at this moment
that a plot began
to formulate in my mind.
The physician told me
if I heated this powder,
it would give me arsenic.
Which is lethal in minute doses.
In its sandarac form,
this shouldn't be enough
to kill.
Unlike arsenic,
this doesn't even dissolve
when mixed in water.
Such a truly ungraceful stone.
In that sense, you could say
it is just like me.
♪
[Boraqchin coughing]
I see.
That dose is enough
to cause this?
Now, all that remains...
is to find what cures it.
Sandarac poison leaves the body
after three months
of recuperation.
But was there no faster,
more dramatic remedy
I could use?
One that would seem
like a miracle?
That was my question
when I finally met that girl.
♪
[BORAQCHIN] What do I do?
One false move,
and this plan will put
the Great Kha'an's life
in peril.
[Boraqchin exhales]
[chuckles]
[laughing]
Obviously, I should
entrust all of our fates
into the hands of Tengri,
shouldn't I?
A divination!
We must perform one at once!
[birds chirping]
[SLAVE] Huh?
Here will do.
So is everything prepared?
Oh, well, divinations require
sheep bones,
but we don't have any.
The fire isn't to heat up bones.
[SLAVE] Huh?
Listen well. Cover your nose
and mouth with a cloth.
And don't stand downwind
of the fire.
[SLAVE] Uh?
[BORAQCHIN] Did you not hear me?
Cover yourself at once.
[SLAVE] Oh, right.
[SLAVE] The red powder
is turning white in the fire?
[gasps]
A good omen.
[slave breathes shakily]
[BORAQCHIN] Sure enough.
From there, everything proceeded
exactly as planned.
♪
[inhales]
[Boraqchin exhales]
Yes, all as planned.
-[MÖGE] Boraqchin?
-Uh?
The Great Kha'an is here.
So listen, Boraqchin,
do you remember
what you had said to me?
"To ensure the Mongols
are not divided,
and to ensure
our hearts remain as one."
You said I should take action.
Tell me, have I let you down?
[BORAQCHIN] Möge, you're fine
just the way you are.
As honest and as kind as ever.
But what does that all mean?
Don't you worry about a thing.
If you say so, Boraqchin.
♪
[BORAQCHIN] Möge...
you don't need
to concern yourself
with any of this.
This is a wager
that I've thrown myself into
completely on my own.
[Ögedei chuckles]
[BORAQCHIN] I apologize
for the wait, Great Kha'an.
There's something
you wished to discuss?
Yes, I have a proposal.
It is about that woman.
Tolui's widow,
Sorghaghtani Beki.
-[QADAQ] Get out of here.
-[SITARA] I won't.
Please, leave us!
I won't! I'm sorry!
[Güyük trembling]
I know that you want
to help Lady Töregene.
Today is not the day.
I see.
-[gasps]
-Uh?
[grunts] Wait!
Prince Güyük! Your mother
also means a great deal to me.
Please. If there's
anything you can tell me,
for her sake, you must.
[Güyük trembles]
-[SHIRA] Hey.
-[BOTH] Uh?
So, someone's coming.
Hey!
[Sitara gasps]
I've seen that woman.
She serves under
Empress Boraqchin.
No matter what,
we can't let her find out
we're here.
[SHIRA] What do we do?
[SITARA] Good question.
[ALL] She's here now!
She's here now!
♪
[Güyük groans]
[LADY-IN-WAITING] Hm.
Mm... A good day to you,
Prince Güyük.
And you, Sir Qadaq.
[QADAQ] I trust
Lady Töregene's safe and sound?
[LADY-IN-WAITING] Of course.
In fact, I've come to inform you
that they're all ready
to release her.
[both gasp]
-[LADY-IN-WAITING] Mm?
-[QADAQ] Huh?
[Qadaq groans, sneezes]
Sorry, continue.
Right.
There are a number
of conditions, however.
[SITARA] Conditions?
[LADY-IN-WAITING]
First, Lady Töregene
appears quite weary.
She will spend her time quietly
in Prince Güyük's territory
from now on.
[SITARA]
So they don't want her returning
to the emperor's court?
[LADY-IN-WAITING]
And there's one more thing.
As a final stipulation
of her being released,
the prince must marry
Princess Sorghaghtani.
[gasps]
All right,
we understand your conditions.
But we need to think it over.
Do think carefully
about what's best for her.
And for all of the Mongols
as well.
With that, I must go.
[Güyük trembling]
[sighs]
I'd say you held out quite well.
-Uh...
-[SITARA] Excuse me.
About what she just said...
[Qadaq groans]
[SHIRA] Uh...
[birds squawking]
So, in other words,
all of this is a part
of the Great Khatun's plot.
Her main goal is to weaken
the House of Tolui.
And then vest the Great Kha'an
with more authority.
To accomplish this,
she needed Prince Tolui
to not simply perish,
but to look like
he sacrificed himself
for the Great Kha'an.
[Boraqchin chuckles softly]
That means
the Great Kha'an's ailment was--
Yes. She used Lady Töregene
in her scheme
to give him poison.
One that wouldn't
quite kill him.
[SITARA] Rahj al-gar.
To carry out her plan,
she tested the poison
on herself.
[Ögedei breathes uneasily]
[SITARA]
Using alchemy to orchestrate
people's lives and deaths.
As a witch would.
[QADAQ] And she's even gotten
Prince Güyük involved in this...
making him marry the princess.
[SHIRA]
Nothing to object to, right?
Seems like it's the only way to
bring Lady Töregene back to us.
[Qadaq sighs]
Well, that is true.
Yes, but still...
-[SITARA] Prince Güyük!
-Uh?
Oh, please, please rescue
Lady Töregene.
I beg of you!
[GÜYÜK] Hmm.
[breathes nervously]
[sighs]
-[GÜYÜK] I'll do it.
-[Sitara exclaims]
[bleating]
So long. I should be returning
to Princess Sorghaghtani.
-Hold on.
-Uh?
You cannot tell anyone
what we talked about.
[SHIRA] Understood. [chuckles]
I sure hope so.
You must feel so relieved.
[grunts]
Now you'll be able
to save the one you wanted to.
Thank you, Shira.
It was reassuring
having you here with me.
Um, right, uh, I'm glad.
[chuckles]
Goodbye.
And may Allah preserve you.
Make sure you keep the secret.
Sure, sure.
[HULEGU] What's that?
My mother? Marry Güyük?
Not a chance!
Yes.
That is what the Great Khatun's
messenger was telling me.
It is clear to me
the House of Ögedei
has dropped all pretense.
The lowly son
of the sixth empress
is completely unfit
to marry her.
That may be, but it is what
the Great Khatun wishes.
♪
[SORGHAGHTANI] I see.
[HULEGU] Mother,
you won't accept this, will you?
I refuse to ever call Güyük
my "father."
Mother? Mother? [stutters]
Mother!
[Shira sighs]
She seems pretty spiritless.
Maybe it would've helped
if I mentioned
who killed Prince Tolui, too.
I never thought
Princess Sorghaghtani
would remarry.
Mm. In the near future,
our two houses
will further join hands.
I was about to send a messenger
to go and speak
with the princess.
Well then, in that case,
could you let me have the honor?
-You want to go?
-Yes.
You gave me the book
I've wanted all this time,
which is truly precious
to someone born to scholars.
So, I want to repay
your kindness.
Oh?
I'm well-acquainted
with the princess.
And I feel certain
I can persuade her without fail.
I see. Intriguing.
[SITARA] It's been three years
since last we spoke.
That is the role of someone
who will be empress one day.
[SITARA] Now that the princess
has been reduced to this,
how will she react
when she sees me again?
Will she be angry?
Will she start yelling?
That's fine by me.
The anger I feel towards her
burns far more intensely
than she could imagine.
Pardon me.
[SORGHAGHTANI] Fatima?
It's been so long.
Yes, I've been away
for quite some time now.
Please forgive me.
You see, I... [gasps]
♪
Shira did tell me that
she was terribly despondent.
I am here today as a messenger
for the Great Khatun.
I'm sorry for the loss
of your husband.
I wish there was something
I could have done.
-It's all right.
-Mm?
♪
Please take a look at this.
It's a fine gift
from the Great Khatun.
Also...
I've come to discuss a matter
of great consequence.
One that will affect us all.
Please do not be alarmed.
But I was sent here
because she asks
that you marry Prince Güyük--
-I'll do as she says.
-Uh?
Huh?
[SORGHAGHTANI] If it will serve
the Mongol people in any way,
then do with me as you see fit.
[SITARA] What?
You can't be serious.
[gasps]
Impossible.
You, who robbed me
of everyone I loved...
♪
[indistinct chatter]
You, in all your arrogance...
You gave up hope after losing
someone you cared about?
[Sitara breathes shakily]
What's wrong?
I admire you.
No, I need to look up at her.
I just have to give her a smile,
like I always do.
[breathes shakily]
There is no one left
to protect you.
[panting]
If you want to shut down
and yield to her,
then suit yourself.
But even though
I've lost the ones
who were truly precious to me,
I'll never give up hope.
[Sorghaghtani gasps]
[SITARA] Stop sulking.
I will continue thinking
for myself.
♪
Now then, the matter
at hand is the remarriage
of Princess Sorghaghtani
to Prince Güyük.
Yes, Sorghaghtani Beki
has consented.
Do you have any objections,
Prince Güyük?
[sighs]
I hope this marriage
forges a new bond
between the Houses
of Ögedei and Tolui.
How heartwarming.
[SITARA]
It was unwise for me
to behave as I did with
Princess Sorghaghtani.
Well, I feel certain
we won't ever meet again.
♪
[indistinct chatter]
[SITARA] Mm?
Uh?
[gasps]
Finally, the date of the wedding
ceremony will be set for--
-[SORGHAGHTANI] Wait a moment.
-[BOTH] Uh?
[all exclaim]
I'm afraid
preparations won't be needed.
[MAN 1] Wait.
Princess Sorghaghtani!
[MAN 2] What does that mean?
-[all gasp]
-[MAN] Why won't they be needed?
[gasping]
[SORGHAGHTANI] Sweet Tolui,
I learned what it's like
to lose someone
for the very first time.
[Tolui laughs]
[SORGHAGHTANI]
And to give up all hope.
-[Tolui breathes uneasily]
-[Sorghaghtani cries]
[SORGHAGHTANI] Oh, Tolui.
Do you think
this is how she felt?
I hope you'll forgive me,
Great Kha'an and Great Khatun.
But you see...
I've chosen to decline
this marriage offer.
[Boraqchin grunts]
[SITARA (ADULT)] Next time,
"The Steppe, Ever Unchanging."